亲爱的 你弄来些啥玩意儿啊
Honey, what is all this?
老妈 我在纠结大学申请的论文题目
Hey, Mam, I'm trying to write these stupid college essay questions.
但我真不知道该如何下笔
And I really even don't know how to start.
好吧 告诉我是什么题目
OK, what's the question? Tell me.
你有生以来遇到的需要克服的最大困难是什么
"what's the biggest obstacle you've ever had to overcome?"
我三年级的老师是不是说
Didn't my third grade teacher say
我有注意力不足症什么的
I had,Like, A.D.D. or something?
不 宝贝儿 她是说你不会做加法
Oh, no, honey. She said you couldn't ADD.
她用字母说明 是因为她知道你也不会拼写
and she put it that way because she also knew you couldn't s-p-e-l-l.
等一下 慢点 原来如此啊
Wait,slow down... Oh...
亲爱的
Sweet heart.
究竟啥玩意儿
What's this?
我们上周讨论过了不是吗
We talked about this last week.
我说要给卢克建个小木屋 你说好吧
I said i'm building luke a tree house. You said "fine."
有时候 我觉得你总是否定我要做的事
You know,sometimes I think you just tune me out.
我从没跟她说过 因为肯定会被她一票否决
I never told her. She just would have said "No."
菲尔 我不记得同意过这事儿
I don't remember agreeing to this, Phil.
就像上次 你在车上装滑翔翼扮大雁
This is like the time you backed down the driveway
倒出车道 都是先斩后奏
with a hang glider sticking out of the car.
如果当初你不阻止我
If you'd let me keep that,
那些鹅就会跟着我滑向湿地了
Those geese would have followed me to the wetlands.
-你会死的 -死的光荣
-You would have died. -A hero.
于是我们铺开毯子
So we spread out a nice blanket,
打开一瓶红酒
opened up a bottle of vino,
然后欣赏日落海平线
and watched the sun set over the water.
好壮丽哦
It was majestic.
非常壮丽
Majestic.
为什么我们从来不去野餐
Why? Why we never have the picnic?
谁喜欢坐在毯子上啊 连个靠背都没有
Who wants to sit on a blanket? There's no back support.
但好壮丽的
It's majestic.
上周"小短"带我去看太阳竞技团演出
Last week, Shorty took me to see the cirque du soleil--
有点像马戏团表演 不过更高雅
It's like a circus, but classy.
所以如果你喜欢大象的话
So if you like elephants,
赶紧去看吧
don't hold your breath.
我老婆可爱吧
She's so cute.
杰总是嫌人多 讨厌海滩 厌恶彩虹
Jay hates the crowds, the beach, the rainbows.
彩虹 不就是天上多点颜色嘛
Rainbows? It's just colors in the sky.
至于每次看到都停车拍照吗
Do we have to pull over every time and take a picture?
真可惜 意大利有句俗话说得好 杰
Shame. There's an expression in Italian, Jay--
执子之手 与子偕老
Dammi la tua mano e corriamo uniti per tutta la vita.
"手牵手 我们一起走 把你一生交给我"
"Give me your hand and we will run together our whole lives."
杰也不喜欢"走"
Jay also hates running.
您点的东西
Here you go.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
-这是您的 -噢 这是什么
-And here you go. -Oh. What is this?
您说要让您"哇"地一声惊喜嘛
You said to knock your socks off.
快看 "袜"子已经不见了哦
Oh, well, look. It's already working!
好吧 再来两杯
Well, two more of those,
估计你连内裤都没了哦
and you won't be wearing any underwear either.
-快看 我内裤也 -小卡 坐下坐下
-Oh! Look... -Cam, down. Down.
-过后再给我看吧 -好吧 过后再说
-Maybe later. -Oh, okay, maybe... Maybe later.
你听到吗 那服务员正在跟我调情呢
Did you hear that? Waitress is flirting with me.
不 她没跟你调情
No, no. She's not flirting with you.
只不过是她要小费的伎俩而已
She's--she's trolling for tips, okay?
她一眼就看出你是同性恋了
She totally knows you're gay.
少来了 怎么可能看出来
How would she know I'm gay?
或许是你点那杯酒的方式吧
Uh, maybe it's the way you ordered a drink-a-doodle-doo.
小卡一直痴人说梦 说自己如果是直男
Cam has this crazy theory that if he were straight...
而朱莉亚·罗伯茨单身的话
And Julia Roberts were single...
-他们早就搞到一起了 -才不是痴人说梦
-They'd be dating. -It's not crazy.
我在反歧视艾滋活动中见过她一次
I met her once at an A.I.D.S. Walk,
当时我们火花四溅啊
and our chemistry was palpable.
不 你只不过给了她一瓶水
No, you handed her a bottle of water.
可她的手指在勾搭我
And her fingers lingered.
那是因为你死不放手
Because you wouldn't let go.
在场的所有妹子 爷我想钓谁都能上钩
I could totally pick up any woman in here.
如果你说的上钩 是指把她抱起离开地面
If by that, you mean lift her off the ground,
那我承认 你绝对够力气
then yes, I'll give you that.
爷天生拥有"情场必杀技"
I for sure could be a womanizer.
恐怕你是个变性人
Or you could be someone
刚刚从"女人变身机"里走出来的
who just stepped out of a machine called the womanizer.
好吧 受够你们的讽刺了
Okay, you know what? That's it.
随便挑个妞儿
Pick anyone in here.
如果我能拿到她的电话号码 你就洗一个月的衣服
If I can get their number, you do the laundry for a month.
如果失败了 爷来洗
If I fail, I'll do it.
好吧 洗衣服什么的最讨厌了 就...
Okay. I hate doing laundry. So, um...
那个不行
No, um...
好吧 就这个
Oh, okay. Right here.
她
Her.
好 成交
Okay, great.
很好 先去一下我的基味
Great. Just get rid of my flair...
哇 我们熟悉的小卡哪去了
Whoa. Where did Cam go?
不知道啊 脱胎换骨了啊
I don't know. Where is he?
晚餐实在太丰盛了
Dinner was absolutely wonderful.
太美妙了
Amazing.
对了
Hey, you know what?
明天一起去跳莎莎舞吧
Why don't you guys come salsa dancing with us tomorrow night?
对啊 一起跳很欢乐哦
Oh, yeah! That would be great!
听起来很诱人 我最爱莎莎了
It sounds like so much fun. I love salsa dancing.
杰 我们去跳吧 快看
Jay, let's go salsa dancing with them. Look.
为什么不去
Why not?
我刚买了按次计费的拳击票
I just bought that pay-per-view fight.
那我们互相妥协一下吧
I tell you what-- we'll compromise.
我们去看拳赛 然后去吃"莎莎"
We'll watch the fight. We'll eat salsa.
别带他去了 咱仨去跳吧
Who needs him? Come dancing with us.
算了 我不想当灯泡
Ay, no, I wouldn't want to--
没有啊 你来可是帮我大忙了
No, no! You'd be doing me a favor.
"小短"一跳起来就停不下 让我偶尔歇歇也好
Shorty never wants to stop, and I could use a break.
你听到了吗 杰 我一跳就停不下来哦
You hear that Jay? I never stop.
我只听到她说想喘口气
All I hear is she could use a break.
嗨 天哪 你好吗
Hey! Oh, my god! How are you?
哇 你看起来美极了
Wow. Look at you. You look fantastic.
谢谢 你也是
Thank you. So do you.
我们多久没见了
How long has it been?
-宛如隔世啊 -是啊
-It feels like forever. -Yeah.
我们上次见面是什么时候来着
Um, when is the last time we saw each other?
我想想 好像还是在达夫办的什么活动上吧
Oh, let's see. I think it was at Dave's thing.
好吧 我很抱歉
You know what? I'm sorry.
不知道你听说没有
I don't know if you've heard.
我遭遇了一次可怕的车祸
I was in a terrible car accident,
自从那次昏迷以后
And ever since the coma,
我就记不得谁是谁了
I have a really hard time placing names and faces.
请问你是谁
So who are you again?
噢 天啊 我真抱歉
Oh, my god. I am so sorry.
我只是在跟你套近乎
It was just a clever way to try to approach you.
我们压根儿不认识
We don't know each other.
其实根本就没昏迷这件事儿
I've never been in a coma.
你自找的 你的搭讪太糟糕了
But you so deserved that. That was the worst pick-up ever.
我的神呀
Oh, my god!
你个小滑头 真讨厌
That was genius! And mean!
现在我知道为什么我们是伪老友了
Now I know why we're old fake friends.
不介意请你喝一杯吧
Oh. Can I buy you a drink?
行啊 我叫凯蒂
Yeah. I'm Katie.
我叫卡梅隆
Cameron.
如果她是一个俊男
If she were a hot guy,
我不可能那么顺利上手的
I would never have been that smooth.
真是讽刺
It's ironic.
就像《玛琪的礼物》
Like the gift of the vagi.
好了
There you go.
谢谢 很高兴认识你
Thank you. Nice to meet you.
-我也是 拜拜 -拜
- You, too. Bye! - Bye!
哦也 承让承让
Wham, bam, thank you, Cam.
太假了 你搞到她电话了
Seriously? You got her number?
当然 记得把我的衬衫熨一下
Sure did. and all my shirts get ironed,
接缝要熨得笔直哦
And their seams should appear straight,
要比直男主人还直哦
Just like their owner.
不该用钉子吧 该用螺丝不是吗
Should you be using screws instead of nails?
美国就是钉子建造起来的 孩子
America was built with nails, son.
你国庆节派对上造的露台也是用的钉子
So was that gazebo you built for our 4th of July party.
跟你说 你会喜欢上这个树屋的
I'm telling you, you are gonna love this bad boy.
你知道什么东西爬不上来吗
You know what can't climb trees?
浣熊嘛
Raccoons?
是烦恼
Worries.
浣熊会爬树 也迟早会爬上来的
Raccoons can and will get up here,
所以不要在这里留吃的
so don't leave any food,
要不它们就会为保护地盘而攻击你
or they'll get territorial and attack.
你确定这是个好主意吗
Are you sure this is a good idea?
开玩笑
Are you kidding me?
将来你和你的小伙伴们会在这儿玩得很开心的
You're gonna have so much fun hanging out up here with your buddies.
相信我 等你长大了 一切都会不同了
Trust me, when you get older, it all changes.
-为什么 -生活所迫
- Why? - Well, life gets in the way.
我是不是说了"老婆所迫"
Did I just say "Wife gets in the way"?
有时候我会说错
'cause sometimes I do that.
没有 没说错
Nope, you're good.
你还有很多朋友
And you have lots of friends.
是啊 我有工作上的朋友
Yeah, I have work friends,
我和你妈还有夫妻档朋友
And your mom and I have couples friends,
还有我大学朋友
And there are my college friends,
但是他们各奔前程了
But they're scattered all over the country.
不像以前对着
It's not the same as just shouting out
邻居朋友吼一声
to your neighborhood buddies,
"伙计们 我在树屋上呢" 嗷
"Hey, fellas! I'm up here in the tree house!" Uhh!
得修一修这个 地板
Fix that... board.
做不来啊
I can't do this.
你火什么火
Why are you so frustrated?
因为从来就没有什么困难需要我克服
Because I've never had any obstacles to overcome.
亲爱的 可不是这样的
Oh, honey, that's not true.
是吗 举个例
Really? Name one.
你有乳糖不耐受症
You're lactose-intolerant.
哦 "亲爱的大学 奶酪让我屁多多
Oh, "Dear college, cheese makes me gassy.
9月见"
See you in September."
亲爱的 你该不会把"亲爱的大学"作为
Sweetie, you're not really starting your essays
你论文的开头吧
"Dear college," Are you?
那又怎么了
What difference does it make?
我活在你们的庇护下 日子无聊而苦逼
I've lived a boring, sheltered, pathetic life.
让你日子过得太滋润了 真是对不起啊
I am sorry we have made things too easy and comfortable for you.
你应该道歉 都是你的错
Oh, you should be! It is all your fault!
你老是护着我
You have shielded me
任何有趣和危险的事情都不让我去干
from everything interesting and dangerous!
你是在指责我
You are blaming me
保护你不受伤害吗
because I kept you from getting hurt?
加布的妈妈是收藏癖
Gaby's mom's a hoarder.
她写论文就毫无障碍
That essay practically writes itself.
可能是我们的错
Maybe it is our fault.
但是你有没有想过原因
But did you ever consider there's a reason?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我们对你那么娇惯 是有原因的
There's a reason why we were so easy on you.
我迷糊了
I don't understand.
亲爱的 你已经不小了
Oh, honey, you're old enough now.
什么不小了
Old enough for what?
该告诉你真相了
The truth.
跟我来 给你看样东西
Okay, come on. Gotta show you somethin'.
我们要开车去
We're gonna go for a ride.
妈 跟我说就是了嘛
Mom, just tell me.
你是我亲妈 对吧
You are my mom, right?
我是个坏人
I'm a bad man.
哦 不 你吃啥了
Oh, no. What did you eat?
米奇尔 记得昨天晚上那女孩吗
Mitchell, remember the girl I met last night?
终身难忘啊
How can I forget her?
她的"辨基能力"全世界倒数第一
She's super famous for having the world's worst gay-dar.
我怎么能无视她的感情呢
How could I be so cavalier with her emotions?
你知道我们心有灵犀
You know, we had a real connection.
她把电话给了我
She gave me her number,
现在她很可能坐在电话旁边
And right now she's probably sitting by the phone
等我的电话
waiting for me to call.
我觉得你不懂我让她多着迷
I don't think you understand how charmed she was by me.
老天 你这自信从哪里来的
Oh, my god. Where did you get all this self-confidence?
1974年的杰斯珀集市会上 我赢得了最可爱宝宝奖
I won cutest baby at the 1974 Jasper County Fair.
那时人们说我像嘉小宝
People at the time said I could go Gerber.
我决定了 我要打电话给她
You know what? I'm calling her.
什么
What?
不行 我不能一直拖着
No, I can't carry this around.
我得跟她说实话 让她放下我
I have to come clean so she can move on with her life.
这太疯狂了 人家才不会等
This is crazy. She is not waiting--
嘿 凯蒂 我是小卡
Hi. Katie. It's Cam.
电话一响她就接了
First ring.
我也很期待打电话给你
I was hoping I would call, too.
真顺啊
Oh, smooth.
昨晚 我有些事没有说
So listen, I forgot to mention something last night,
我不知道该如何说起
and I'm--I'm actually not really quite sure how to say this.
我是个同志
I'm a gay guy.
其实是个比较微妙的话题
Um, it's actually somewhat delicate.
就像我一样娇柔 因为我是同志
As am I, on account of the gay.
不 凯蒂 那天我也聊得很愉快
No, no, I had a great time with you, too, Katie.
只是 只是
It's--well, it's just that--
-我对妹子不敢兴趣 -不 你坐下来
- I don't dig the ladies. - No, no. And I want you to sit--
你先在卧榻上坐稳了
I want you to have a seat on a chaise lounge.
想在比赛开始前
Hey, you wanna go out and
出去吃个晚饭吗
grab some dinner before the fight tonight?
不用 多谢了
No, thank you.
想在家里自己开伙吗
Wanna eat at home?
我来烤点牛排 开瓶小酒
I'll grill some steaks, open a bottle of wine.
随你便 我晚上要出去
Whatever you want, because I'm not going to be here.
她要出去跳莎莎舞 居然不带我
She's going Salsa Dancing without me.
曼尼 我说了那俱乐部得年满21岁才能进
Ay, Manny, I told you, it's a 21 and over club.
小学生禁入的舞所 才散发致命的诱惑
A forbidden dance floor. Only makes me want it more.
等一下 你要同"小短"和达琳去跳舞吗
Wait a second. You're going dancing with Shorty and Darlene?
没错 虽然他和你年纪一样大
Yes, because even though he's old like you,
可他仍然喜欢出去找乐子
he still likes to have fun.
我们也喜欢找乐子啊
We like to have fun.
上周我还带你去吃晚饭了呢
Last week I took you to dinner,
还看了船展
went to the boat show,
还品尝了冰冻果子露
got some sherbet?
结果一艘船也没买 才8点半就回家了
And we were home by 8:30 with no boat.
你想要我怎么做 我不喜欢跳舞
What do you want from me? I don't like dancing.
-我还不喜欢果子露呢 -是吗
- I don't like sherbet. - Yeah, right.
那椰子呢
How about coconut?
谁不喜欢椰子啊 谁 谁啊
Who doesn't like the coconut, hmm? Who?
不管你去不去 反正我要去跳舞
And anyways, I'm going dancing with or without you.
行 我祝你和"小短"玩得愉快
Fine. I hope you have a good time with Shorty.
我才不要和"小短"跳
I don't need Shorty!
我随便找个舞伴 简直手到擒来
I won't have any problem finding a partner on my own!
妈 你又戳到我的痛处了
Wow. Way to rub it in, mom.
谈得如何啊 爱情杀手
How'd it go, heartbreaker?
她真是个优雅的女士
That is one classy lady...
-所以我对她开不了口 -啥
- Which is why I couldn't tell her. - What?
我没法在电话上说这事
Well... I just couldn't do it on the phone.
她接到我的电话时那么开心
She seemed so excited to hear from me,
我又不擅长伤别人的心 米奇尔
and I'm very bad at disappointing people, Mitchell.
我心已伤
Not all people.
我妈说的对
Mama was right when she said
她说我的魅力好比脱缰的种马
my charm was like a wild stallion--
如果控制不当 定将毁家灭棚
If not properly bridled, it'll bust down a barn.
你想甩掉你的女友吗
Okay, you wanna get rid of your girlfriend?
把你妈的话复述一遍就是了
Tell her that story.
她过来时我会说的 她一会儿就到
Maybe I will when she comes over. She's coming over.
你没开玩笑吧
Are you serious?
她说她正在附近办事
She said she was in the area running errands.
那我能说什么 别来我家
What was I supposed to say, "Don't come over"?
也许我是该那么说
Well, I guess I could have said that,
可为时已晚
but it's too late now,
而且我想温柔地和她分手
Plus I wanna break it to her gently.
所以 快来帮我将此地"去基化"
So come on. Help me un-gay this place.
我干脆走掉 就少了一半基味了
You know what? I'll make it less gay by half.
这些花也得藏起来
Oh, these flowers should go, too.
你是说那些放在
You mean the ones underneath
你和某男勾肩搭背的照片下的花吗
the portrait of you cuddling another man?
说得对
Oh, good catch.
曼尼
Manny.
什么事 老爹
What's up, big guy?
那个莎莎舞是不是很难学
How hard is it to learn this salsa dancing stuff?
一点都不难
Not hard at all.
重点是在舞步中带入你的感情
It's about tapping into your emotion,
你的激情 你心中暗藏的火焰
your passion, and your inner fire.
狗屁
Crap!
我跳舞超烂
I stink at dancing.
我们跳婚礼上的第一支舞时
First dance at our wedding,
歌洛莉亚集优雅与华丽为一身
Gloria was all graceful and gorgeous,
我则是又笨又拙的大块头
and I was all big and clunky.
就像动画片《美女与野兽》里的那一幕
Like that scene from "Beauty and the beast."
事实上 我们用的就是同名主题曲
Actually, that was the song.
是曼尼选的
Manny picked it.
当时他诚心让我出丑
He didn't like me back then.
背挺直 很好
Back straight. Okay.
跟我一起做
Do as I do.
另一只脚
Other leg.
别像行军一样
Okay, stop marching.
你是在跳舞 不是德军入侵波兰
You're dancing, not invading Poland.
爷俩好啊
Hello, hi!
我想找一下杰·普里契特
I'm looking for Jay Pritchett.
他身高188 硬汉一个
He's about 6'2", tough guy,
努力克服着恐同症
wrestles with homophobia...
你来这干嘛
The hell are you doing here?
我得离开家门
Uh, I had to get out of the house.
小卡和他的新女友要单独处处
Cam needed a little alone time with his new girlfriend.
-别问 -别说
- Don't ask. - Don't tell.
你们在干嘛
What's going on here?
他在学怎么跳舞 可他太僵硬
He's learning to dance, but he's just so tense.
-完全不行 -因为你放不开自己
- It's not working out. - 'cause you're not letting go.
我尽力了 你以为我不想舞步翩翩
I'm trying. Don't you think I want to be all smooth
博得你妈笑开颜吗
and make your mom happy out there?
可我就是不会跳舞 就这样
But I just can't do it, that's all.
杰 我不会放弃你的
Jay, I'm not giving up on you.
好了 曼尼 能让我们单独聊聊吗
Okay. Hey, Manny, would you give us a second?
谢了
Thanks.
爸 我知道这样做有点怪
Dad, look, I-I know this is weird,
但我们爷俩其实很像
but you and I are a lot alike.
我们都太扭捏了
We're self-conscious, okay?
所以 这个
So, um, here. Just...
这是啥玩意儿
The hell is this?
就是有些人会在夜店吃的那种东西
It's just something that some people take at clubs
用来放松自己
to, you know, loosen up.
你吃过这玩意儿?
You take this?
一个痛恨跳舞的基佬
A gay man who hates dancing
只能烂在自己的孤独小世界里
Lives in a sad and lonely little world.
这玩意儿能让你不再拘谨
This just melts your inhibitions,
让你激情欢跳一整晚
And--and you can dance all night,
同时也能让你"性致"大发...
Plus it gives you a raging--
我不想听
I don't wanna--
我不喜欢搞歪门邪道
I don't like this at all.
你就拿着吧 以防万一
Just hold on to it. Just in case.
好啦 没事
Come on. It's fine.
杰 我要给你看点东西
Jay, I wanna show you something.
一位新西兰的农民教会一头猪翩翩起舞
A farmer in new zealand taught a pig to dance.
瞧人家猪兄那鼻子挺的
See how he keeps his snout up?
对 就是这里
Yep. This is it.
来这儿干嘛
This is what?
这个
This.
我 我做不到 我没办法下车
I-I can't do this. I can't get out of the car.
对不起 我太难为情了
I'm sorry. I'm too embarrassed.
你能不能告诉我到底怎么回事
Would you just tell me what's going on?
好吧 我需要你读一下
Okay. I-I want you to go read
刻在那棵树上的字
what's carved in that tree.
妈 你有点吓着我了
Mom, you're freaking me out.
照做就行了 去读吧 海莉
Just do it. Do it, Haley.
回家路上玩的开心呦
Have fun getting home!
摆在你眼前的就是困难
There's your obstacle!
什么 你跟我开玩笑呢吧
What?! Are you kidding me?!
妈的...
Oh! Son of a...
擦啊 怎么老是这样
Brisket! Why does that keep happening?
或许我需要个射钉枪
Maybe I need a nail gun.
得嘞 行了 我不玩了
Okay, that's it! I'm out!
什么意思 你不玩了
What do you mean, you're out?
你去哪啊
Where are you going?
老爸 恕我冒犯
Dad, no offense,
我见识过您拿喷胶枪搞出什么状况
But I've seen you with a glue gun.
要是把钉子弄进我脑袋 可比胶水难伺候多了
I think a nail is gonna be harder to get out of my hair.
别 别走啊 我建这个可是为了你啊
No, don't go! I'm doing this for you!
是吗 老爸
Are you, dad?
是吗
Are you?
孩子的话令我深思
The kid made me think with that one.
我做这个到底是为了谁
Who was I really doing this for?
有的时候我只要一说
Sometimes I just say,
"是吗 老爸 是吗"
"Are you, dad? Are you?"
老爸就会沉默不语
Because he gets real quiet
而且不会意识到我已经闪人了
And doesn't notice when I walk away.
好奇怪啊
It's weird,
只要在你身边 我就觉得很心安
because I feel so comfortable around you already.
昨晚我回到家后
You know, last night when I got home,
我就开始想那些
I just started thinking about
我们可以一起做的趣事 知道吗
all of the fun things that we could do together, you know?
是啊
Yeah.
我不想把你吓跑
I don't wanna scare you off,
但是我姐姐几周后就要结婚了
But my sister's getting married in a couple of weeks,
我可不想一个人参加婚礼
And I so don't wanna go to that thing alone.
或许你可以做我的男伴
Maybe you could be my date?
凯蒂 你是个很好的女人
Katie, you're an amazing woman.
你聪明 又美丽
You're smart, you're beautiful,
而且手袋都那么好看
And how fun is that handbag?
我接下来要说的 你可能会有点震惊
This is gonna come as a little bit of a shock.
我是个货真价实的基佬
I'm fairly gay.
我不知道我怎么冒出这么一句
I don't know why I said that.
我 我是个彻头彻尾的基佬
I'm--I'm totally gay.
基的无可救药
Just gay.
你是在告诉我你是同性恋吗
You're telling me you're gay?
是啊
Yeah.
为什么
Why?
我生来如此 我是说 你知道...
I was born that way. I mean, you know, it's just--
不是 你干嘛告诉我啊
No, why are you telling me?
我是说 我早知道你是同性恋啊
I mean, I know you're gay.
很明显啊
It's obvious.
也没...也不是那么明显吧
Well, it's not that-- it's not that obvious.
基爆了啊
Well, yeah.
你说话 走路 穿衣的方式
The way you talk and walk and dress
还有你那很戏剧性的手势
And your theatrical hand gestures--
我没什么戏剧性的手势
I do not have theatrical hand gestures.
好吧 我确实有点...基态外露
Okay, maybe I am moderately...expressive.
但你干嘛给我你的电话号码啊
But why would you give me your number?
因为我想有一个基佬闺蜜啊
Oh, because I want a gay friend--
一个能陪我闲聊八卦
Someone I can dish with,
给我男生的建议 也可以一起血拼
Give me guy advice, and I can shop with--
那些绝对是世人对同志陈旧片面的认识
Those are totally offensive stereotypes.
我们可以一起去看茱莉亚·罗伯茨的电影
We could go see Julia Roberts movies together.
我知道她 而且她无论银幕内外都很美
I know her, and she's as nice as she seems on screen.
-不是吧 真的吗 -当然是
- Shut up. Really? Is she? - She is, yeah.
等等 如此说来 你是想假装成直男
Wait, what--so you were pretending to be straight,
然后勾搭我
And hitting on me?
只不过是个愚蠢的酒吧赌罢了
I was just a stupid bar bet.
我男友 他回来了
My boyfriend--oh, he's here...
打赌说没有哪个美女会留电话号码给我
Bet me that I couldn't get a beautiful woman's number.
身为一个自豪的同志 我知道女人都是浮云
And as a proud gay man, I know it shouldn't matter,
但 我就是希望自己的魅力能通杀男女
But I-I just wish everyone could find me attractive.
但是 现在轮到他幸灾乐祸了
Oh. But now he's gonna get to gloat,
不过这也是我活该
And I guess I deserve it.
我的天啊[唇语]
Oh my god!
谈得 谈得怎么样啊
How's--how's it going?
你好
Hello.
这位是凯蒂 结果发现 事实上 [很好]...
This is Katie, and, uh, it turns out, well...
事实上 不好
No, actually.
进行得相当不好
It doesn't turn out well.
因为我以为我终于找到一位又好又风趣的男人
Because I thought I finally met a nice, funny guy,
而且还超级性感
Who is also hot!
但现在他告诉我说他是同性恋
And now he's telling me he's gay?!
他简直是 我这辈子碰见的最不像同性恋的人
He's, like, the least gay person i have ever met in my entire life!
而且我以为他就是我的真命天子呢
And I thought he was the one!
而且我还告诉我妈呢
And I even told my mom about him!
你最好给我好好珍惜他
You better cherish him!
你确定你是同性恋吗
Are you sure you're gay?
-不确定 -小卡
- No. - Cam.
确定
Yes.
确定 听着
Yes. Look...
你会找到你的真命天子的
You're gonna find somebody,
因为你是个出色的女人 凯蒂
Because you're an amazing girl, Katie.
你是个极品好女人
You're the whole package.
但我喜欢的是有"鸡"的男人
I just prefer somebody who has one.
好吧
Okay.
我 的 天 哪
Oh... My... God!
爷我刚才啃的可是女人的香舌呢
That was a lot of girl tongue!
看来我可得好好喝上一杯了
I think I need a drink-a-doodle-doo.
你那算什么
What was that?
你好啊 海莉 今天过得怎样
Hello, Haley. How was your day?
我身无分文 又没手机
I have no money, no cell phone...
不用谢哦
You're welcome.
你说什么
What?!
我听取了你的意见
I listened to you.
我不再娇惯你了 你看看
I stopped coddling you, and look--
你成功克服了困难
You overcame an obstacle.
是哦 我做到了
Oh! Yeah! I did!
家有疯母 我很庆幸自己是个正常孩子
I grew up normal despite my crazy mom!
拿这句当你的论文开头挺不错的
Well, that sounds like the beginning of a great essay.
亲爱的大学
"Dear college..."
亲爱的 要是你又卡住了 告诉我
Oh, honey, if you get stuck, let me know,
我会让你睡在院子里的
And I'll make you sleep out in the yard.
你是个神经病
You're psychotic!
记得检查拼写哦
Use spell check!
别干坐在那儿 快过来
Don't just sit there! Get out here!
不用了 我很好
I'm good, I'm good.
好吧
Okay!
你好啊 你看上去真漂亮
Hola! You're looking so good!
我们多久没见了
How long has it been?
别装作我们认识 滚开
We don't know each other. Go away.
好吧
Fair enough.
你好啊
Hola!
你看上去真漂亮 我们多久没见了
You're looking so good. How long has it been?
那人怎么不好了
What was wrong with that guy?
就是啊 我都想和他共舞呢
Yeah, I would have danced with him.
他的肩膀超级正
He's got nice shoulders.
跳莎莎舞要与舞伴亲密接触 欲情荡漾
Aw, you know, Salsa is so intimate and sensual
和别的男人跳 感觉好罪恶
that it feels wrong to do it with somebody else that is not Jay.
达琳也是这么觉得的
Aw. You know, Darlene feels the same way.
要是我不在 她会去找道墙
If I wasn't here, she's be holding up the wall.
是啊 男人墙
Yeah. A wall of men.
我觉得我该回家陪我那可爱的老公了
You know, I think I should go home to my loving husband
然后在他耳边说我和20个男人跳了舞
and pull him close and tell him that I danced with 20 men.
他不在家
He's not home.
他此刻身在一个治安差劲的地方
He's in a dicey neighborhood
时刻担心他的车被盗
worried about his car.
杰
Jay!
怎么 你是要亲亲还是要跳舞
What, are we gonna kiss or dance?
舞起来吧
Let's dance!
我是坚决抵制嗑药的
I'm dead set against drugs.
面对禁药 必须坚决说不
"Just say no" And all that stuff.
可我觉得
But I thought,
为了歌洛莉亚破一次例又何妨
Just this once for Gloria.
要是我真嗑高了 出尽洋相
And if I was gonna make a complete ass of myself,
我可不要记起来
I didn't wanna remember it.
我给他的那粒药 其实是儿童阿司匹林 桔子口味
The big drug I gave him-- baby aspirin. Orange-flavored.
他应该咀嚼的
He could have chewed it.
为什么你就从未给我这样的惊喜
Home come you never surprise me like that?
我当然给过你惊喜
I do surprise you.
你才没有 你从来都没有
No, you don't. You never surprise me...
一定会是座很了不起的树屋的
That's gonna be a hell of a tree house.
谢谢关心 我正努力呢
Oh, thanks. I'm trying.
本来为我儿子造的 可貌似他失去兴趣了
It's for my son, but he's kind of lost interest.
和我女儿养狗一样
It's kind of like my daughter with the dog.
最后只能由我来拣狗屎了
Which is why I'm the one out here doing this.
你刚搬进来吗
Did you just move in?
都住了8年了 你呢
Lived here eight years. You?
当年我和我的朋友
You know, me and my friends,
儿时造过一个树屋
We, uh, we built a te house when I was a kid.
当时费了不少时间
We spent hours in that thing.
但很享受
Loved it.
我也一样
Me, too.
需要帮忙吗
You need any help?
当然
Yes, a lot.
可我不想麻烦你
But I-I don't wanna bother you.
唯一让我不爽的
Only thing that bothers me
是你那东倒西歪的屋顶
is that drunken amish roof you got up there.
你没有水平测量仪吗
Do you even have a level?
本来有的 可我感觉有点受挫
I did, but I might have gotten frustrated
一气之下扔到你院子里了
and thrown it into your yard.
我找找看 马上就过来
Let me find it. I'll be right over.
多谢啊
Thanks.
顺便提下 我叫菲尔
I'm Phil, by the way.
我叫安德瑞 很高兴认识你 菲尔
I'm Andre. Nice to meet you, phil.
很高兴认识你 安德瑞
Nice to meet you, Andre.
看来我之前说一旦长大后
So I guess I was wrong when I said once you get older,
很难再交到朋友是错的
it's harder to make new friends.
快看 亲爱的 树上那人酷极了
Hey, honey! There's a dude in the tree that's cool!
安德瑞其实是一个整形医生
Andre, it turns out, is an orthopedic surgeon,
任何工具都得心应手 同时也是个好玩伴
Handy with tools, and a great guy to hang out with.
而且 他是个犀利的黑鬼头
Plus he's a badass black man
让我在社区增加不少威望
that gives me extra street cred.
那个是他编的笑话
That's his joke.
他是我同父异母的兄弟
He's my brotha from a different motha.
-你胡说什么 -异...
- What was that? - Different--
-不是那样的 -那是什么
- That's not it. - What is it?
应该是 亲如兄弟
It's "Brother from another mother."
亲如兄弟
Brotha from anotha motha--
慢慢来 慢慢来
Slow down. Slow it down.
亲如兄弟
Brotha from another motha.
算了 别说了 算了
Forget it. Don't-- just don't say it. Forget it.